<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TourGuideApp</string>
    <string name="Fortresses">Fortresses</string>
    <string name="Churches">Churches</string>
    <string name="NationalParks">National Parks</string>
    <string name="Landmarks">Landmarks</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Drawer is open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Drawer is closed</string>
    <string name="stjohn">This venerable 14th-century lump of stone is famous for the balustraded staircase on the street-facing side, said to be the work of prolific stonemason Nikola Firentinac. Sprouting from the upper part of the balustrade are a series of angels’ heads in relief form, while a severely eroded lion stands guard at the bottom. The church’s four-storey belfry boasts the town’s oldest mechanical clock, made by Ottoman craftsmen and used in Drniš before being brought to Šibenik. Inside lies a trio of Baroque altars; the side altar to the left bears a jolly relief of trumpeting cherubs and skulls. </string>
    <string name="cathedral">The Cathedral of St. James (Croatian: Katedrala sv. Jakova) in Šibenik, Croatia is a triple-nave basilica with three apses and a dome (32 m high inside) in the city of Šibenik, Croatia. It is the church of the Catholic Church in Croatia, and the see of the Šibenik diocese. It is also the most important architectural monument of the Renaissance in the entire country. Since 2000, the Cathedral has been on the UNESCO World Heritage List. The building of the church was initiated in 1402, though plans on its construction had already begun in 1298, when Šibenik became a municipality. The actual work to transform the older Romanesque cathedral began in 1431. Built entirely of stone (limestone from a nearby stone quarry and marble from the island of Brač), it was completed in three phases, from 1433 to 1441, when the Grand City Council entrusted the work to local and Italian masters Francesco di Giacomo, Lorenzo Pincino, Pier Paolo Bussato, Bonino da Milano, and Giorgio da Sebenico (Juraj Dalmatinac) and to Croatian ones Andrija Budčić and Grubiš Šlafčić.</string>
    <string name="churchasc">A church of medieval origins, this plain but alluring stone beauty began life as the Church of the Holy Saviour, and belonged to the Knights Templars then the Brotherhood of Flagellants before becoming the convent church of the Poor Clares in the 15th century. A fire in 1725 occasioned a major rebuild, when a few Baroque details were added. The convent was closed by Emperor Joseph II, and the church was handed over to the Orthodox congregation in 1808. It has been the centre of Šibenik County’s Orthodox community ever since. </string>
    <string name="stmichael">One of the first things that visitors see when entering Šibenik by road is the silhouette of St Michael’s Fortress, which crowns the pyramidal hill above Šibenik’s Old Town. Its importance to the Croatian state is illustrated by the number of times that 11th-century Croatian kings brought their court here – Petar Krešimir IV in 1066, Zvonimir in 1078, and Stjepan II in 1080. It was during Krešimir’s visit that Šibenik was first mentioned in official documents, which explains why the city is sometimes known to this day as “Krešimir’s Town”.
Its floor plan has the shape of an irregular rectangle. There are two square towers on its eastern side whereas two polygonal towers sit along its northern front. Throughout history, the fortress had been repeatedly destroyed and rebuilt, and it experienced its greatest suffering in 1663 and 1752. Archaeological investigations inside the monumental complex have found numerous remains of material culture dating from prehistoric times to the late Middle Ages.
Running downhill from the fortress towards the seafront are a crenellated set of double walls built in the 15th century to provide access to the sea.</string>
    <string name="barone">The Barone Fortress (formerly known as Šubićevac Fortress; Croatian: Tvrđava Barone) in Šibenik, Croatia, is an early modern fortress constructed in 1646 on Vidakuša hill above the city. Together with the remaining three city fortresses, it is a part of the Šibenik fortification system. It played a significant role in city\'s defense from the Ottomans during the Cretan War. For a long time, it carried the name of its main defender, Baron Christoph von Degenfeld. At the start of the 20th century, along with the surrounding neighborhood, it was renamed Šubićevac, after the medieval patrician family Šubić.</string>
    <string name="stjohnfortress">St. John\'s Fortress (also known as Tanaja; Croatian: Tvrđava sv. Ivana) is an early modern fortress in Šibenik, Croatia, situated atop a hill north of the city\'s historical center. Named after a medieval church dedicated to St. John the Baptist that had stood there from at least 1444, the fortress, together with the adjacent Barone Fortress, was built during the Cretan War and successfully repelled consecutive Ottoman attacks in 1646 and 1647. A local name for the fortress, Tanaja, comes from one of its structures, a plier-shaped outwork, or tenaille (Italian tanaglia). </string>
    <string name="stnicholas">St. Nicholas\' Fortress (Croatian: Tvrđava Sv. Nikole) is a fortress located in the town of Šibenik, one of the oldest native Croatian towns on the eastern shores of the Adriatic, in central Dalmatia, Croatia. It was included in UNESCO\'s World Heritage Site list as part of "Venetian Works of Defence between 15th and 17th centuries: Stato da Terra – western Stato da mar" in 2017.The fortress is one of the most valuable and best preserved examples of defense architecture in Dalmatia. It is made of brick because that material was considered to be most resistant to cannonballs, while the foundations are made of stone. Although defense capabilities of the fortress have never been tested in military operations, the structure still proved successful in protecting the city from sea-bound enemy attacks. During the centuries of use, the structure served to various armies and has undergone a number of renovations, some of them necessary only because of the development of arms. It was completely abandoned by the military in 1979 and has been undergoing renovation ever since.</string>
    <string name="krka">Krka National Park is situated along the Krka River in southern Croatia. It\'s known for a series of 7 waterfalls. In the south, Skradinski Buk waterfall is flanked by traditional watermills. To the north, a nature trail passes another striking cascade, Roški Slap, and the Krka Monastery, built above ancient Roman catacombs. Visovac Island is home to the 15th-century Franciscan Monastery of Our Lady of Mercy. Skradinski buk is one of the most attractive parts of the park. It is a massive, clear, natural pool with high waterfalls at one end and cascades at the other. It is the lowest of the three sets of waterfalls formed along the Krka river. In an area 400 m in length and 100 m in width there are 17 waterfalls and the total difference in height between the first and the last falls is 47.7 m. Due to the wealth and variety of geomorphological forms, vegetation, and the various effects caused by the play of light on the whirlpools, Skradinski buk is considered to be one of the most beautiful calcium carbonate waterfalls in Europe.</string>
    <string name="kornati">In 1980, the eighty-nine southernmost of the 140-odd islands, islets and reefs of the Kornati archipelago were declared a national park, Nacionalni Park Kornati, protecting the islands and their marine surroundings. The area covered by the National Park mostly coincides with the Donji Kornati, which includes the island of Kornat and the surrounding islets, separated with a channel from the island of Piškera and the surrounding islets. The national park includes 109 islands, of which 76 are less than 1 hectare in size. Of the total land surface area of Kornati (62 km2), 85% is stony, and only 5% has been cultivated. There are no permanent settlements in Kornati. Simple houses in well-protected coves such as Vrulje, Kravjačica, Lavsa and others are used by mainland landowners as temporary shelters.</string>
    <string name="drazen">Šibenik’s most famous sporting son, Dražen Petrović, is well remembered here. In Baldekin, a part of this coastal town, alongside a memorial centre, you’ll find a court dedicated to this former NBA great.</string>
    <string name="juraj">The great Zadar-born stonemason was resident in Šibenik from 1441 until his death over three decades later, despite long absences working in Split, Dubrovnik, Ancona and elsewhere. Šibenik folk regard him with justification as a local, and this statue on the square outside the Cathedral is very much a statement of municipal patriotism as well as a mark of respect for a great architect.</string>
    <string name="fourwells">In the very center of Šibenik, only 50 meters from the Cathedral of St. Jacob, hides a plateau with an old water supply facility referred to as the 4 Wells, its entrance opposite the entrance to the Cathedral, behind high stone walls. It was used until the middle of the 20th century. </string>
</resources>
